A little pig goes a long way.
Babe is a fantasy, drama, comedy film directed by Chris Noonan.
Babe is a little pig who doesn't quite know his place in the world.
With a bunch of odd friends, like Ferdinand the duck who thinks he is a rooster and Fly the dog he calls mum, Babe
realises that he has the makings to become the greatest sheep pig of all time, and Farmer Hoggett knows it.
With the help of the sheep dogs, Babe learns that a pig
can be anything that he wants to be.
Babe (voice), played by Christine Cavanaugh.
Fly (voice), played by Miriam Margolyes.
Ferdinand (voice), played by Danny Mann.
Rex (voice), played by Hugo Weaving.
Maa (voice), played by Miriam Flynn.
Farmer Hoggett, played by James Cromwell.
Babe is a 1995 comedy-drama film directed by Chris
Noonan, who co-wrote it with George Miller.
It is an adaptation of Dick King-Smith's 1983 novel The Sheep-Pig, which tells
the story of a farm pig who wants to do the work of a sheepdog.
The film is narrated by Roscoe Lee Browne and the main animal characters
are played by both real animals and animatronic puppets.
Babe was filmed in Robertson, New South Wales, Australia, in 1994 and released theatrically in the United States and Canada on 4 August 1995,
going on to become a critical and commercial success with seven Academy Award nominations, including Best Director and Best Picture.
A sequel, Babe: Pig in the City, was released in 1998, with most
of the starring actors reprising their roles.
However, it did not perform as well commercially or critically as the original.
The film explores themes of farm, sheep, pig, alarm clock, cat.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.